Nagaraj Alagusundaram

Lidcombe, NSW

me@nagaraj.com.au



0415250335



linkedin.com/in/nalagusundaram



https://www.nagaraj.com.au

Summary

My name is Nagaraj Alagusundaram but you can call me Nag.

Hands-on experience with Java, Kotlin, Android SDK, Rest APIs, Git, Dart, Flutter, and other tech principles and culture via both team/individual projects, code reviews, and pair programming.

Experienced in

- * developing a bank-level security app.
- * Implementing TDD
- * Creating pipelines from scratch for Native Android, iOS, Xamarin & Flutter projects.
- * Azure DevOps, Agile
- * Contributing to Opensource projects
- * git (Github, Gitlab, Bitbucket)

To know more visit my portfolio: https://www.nagaraj.com.au

I love making new professional acquaintances. Reach out if you want to talk about technology, business, chess, cricket.

Experience

*xam Senior Software Engineer

XAM Consulting

Sep 2020 - Present (7 months +)

Working for Link group

LINK Software Engineer (on-site via Xam Consulting)

Link Group (LNK)

Sep 2019 - Present (1 year 7 months +)

Working on different projects within the company as a Mobile App developer (both iOS & Android)

To develop apps I'm currently using

Languages:

- * Java
- * Kotlin
- * C#
- * Swift

Framework:

Xamarin.Forms

Azure:

- * Pipelines
- * Repo
- * Boards

Stores:

Monitor for crashes and provide a fix, if any.

Responsibilities:

- * Fix the existing bugs
- * Add new features
- * Build and provide the artifacts to the testing team
- * Generate the certificates and keystores
- * Publish the prod apps to the stores (iOS & Android)

*xam Software Developer

XAM Consulting

Sep 2019 - Sep 2020 (1 year 1 month)

Working for Link group

Software Engineer

AGAM Solutions

Mar 2019 - Sep 2019 (7 months)

Developed an app using Flutter for the Tamil Nadu government (https://tbpspilot.nirt.res.in/).

A survey app for the district-wise prevalence of Microbiologically confirmed pulmonary Tuberculosis in Tamil Nadu.

The app was launched by Dr. Radhakrishnan, IAS.

The app collects the basic details of the household and sync's the data with the server when there is an internet connection.

Responsibilities:

- * Developed the app from scratch
- * Followed TDD approach
- * Publishing the app to the internal stores
- * Provided continuous support on the minor upgrades
- * Upgraded the App to flutter 2.0

Contractor

iCodeNext Ptv Ltd

Sep 2018 - Jan 2019 (5 months)

Hired people from India to develop a website and apps for the product.

Tech Lead

Bahwan CyberTek

Apr 2016 - Aug 2018 (2 years 5 months)

Responsibility includes:

- * Scrum Master
- * Working on Android app (dropthought)
- * Code review
- * Managing the stores
- * Reporting to the manager
- * Hiring new people and conducting technical interviews

Freelance Android App Developer

TNE Software Solutions

Apr 2015 - Mar 2016 (1 year)

Responsibilities include:

Working on apps on request.

Delivering the apps on time

Writing test cases

Upgrading the old Android code

Working on the opensource VPN connection

U: Senior Software Engineer

UST

Nov 2013 - Mar 2015 (1 year 5 months)

Responsibilities include:

- * Developing IVR applications
- * Developing Android apps
- * Training people on Android
- * Updating the task to the client every Thursday
- * Publishing the new features to the production

Senior Software engineer - IVR

Planet41 Mobi-Venture Ltd.

Jul 2012 - Oct 2013 (1 year 4 months)

Responsibilities include:

- * Developing new features to the existing IVR applications
- * Unit test and bug fixing
- * launching the IVR application

Learning to develop Android apps on own interest.

Software Engineer - Voice Developer

Nuance Communications

Jan 2012 - Jul 2012 (7 months)

Software Engineer - IVR Developement

Cellcast

Sep 2010 - Dec 2011 (1 year 4 months)

Responsibilities include:

Develop IVR applications using VC++

Calling the Dialogic services

Publish the application to production

Senior Engineer

LatticeBridge Infotech Pvt. Ltd.

Jun 2008 - Aug 2010 (2 years 3 months)

Responsibilities include:

Developing IVR applications

Implementing the new features/flows

Fetching and sending the performance report

Support and maintenance of the existing the IVR applications

Education



B.Tech, C.S.E 2004 - 2008

Kamala Subramaniam School & Trust

SSLC

2000 - 2002

Licenses & Certifications



Issued Jul 2019 - Expires Jul 2022 883ee1b662a143c1983fd9b7c566df3f

Skills

Android • Flutter • Kotlin • Android Development • Software Development • Mobile Applications • Scrum • Agile Methodologies • Android SDK • Java

Honors & Awards

Puts the Client First - HariKrishnan Krishnakumar Nov 2014

Most Active Contributor Award - Dave Webb

Nov 2014

- Beat Team Player Award Mohan Ram Sep 2009
- Best Team Player 2017 Durga Prasad
 Dec 2017
- Xam Social Hero XAM
 Jan 2021